reclaimthenet.org 2019-06-14

# Privacy Policy

This privacy policy describes the information practices of websites operated by ReclaimTheNet.org (“us”, “we”, “Reclaim the Net”, etc.).

Reclaim the Net does not collect or share your personal information by default.

**Website Analytics Records**

When you visit a website, your IP address is part of every request you send. We record information about each request we receive indefinitely, however we collect that IP data in anonymized form, meaning you can't be personally identified from it.

For example, if you're a visitor from Sweden, we can tell that we've had a visit from a region from Sweden but we can't link it to you personally. We use Clicky.com for this.

**An Email Address**

If you ask us to keep in touch with you by email, either through our newsletter or a course, we’ll send you updates about news, tutorials, features, products and tools you may be interested in. Every email we send includes an unsubscribe link. Our email newsletters are delivered by a 3rd party Aweber. You can read their privacy policy [here](https://www.aweber.com/privacy.htm). Aweber may also collect your IP address.

**Payment Data**

If you choose to purchase a product or donate to Reclaim The Net then your payment data is managed and held offsite through Stripe payments.

**Embedded Content**

YouTube videos are embedded in [privacy-enhanced mode](https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/171780?hl=en-GB).

Twitter embedded videos are doing so in a way that [opts out](https://developer.twitter.com/en/docs/twitter-for-websites/privacy.html) of your data being used for personalization.

**Comments**

We use a 3rd party comments system for managing comments. Please review the [privacy policy](https://commento.io/privacy) for the comments system if you wish to sign up to leave a comment.

**Policy Changes**

Whenever we make a change to our practices, we’ll update this policy.
